

CONTACT ME AT

- #894, 2nd floor, 11th Main, 5th B Cross,Vijayabank layout, SRS nagar,BG road, Bangalore 560076
- anirudh.anirudh93@gmail.com
- (+91)-9036565202
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/anirudh
- https://github.com/ukanirudh
- http://anirudhuk.in/

SKILLS SUMMARY

Javascript, HTML & CSS
React and Redux

Angular framework

Jest and Storybook

Highcharts and Ag-grid

Graphql and Rest-Apis

Typescript

RXJS and NGXS

GIT

AWARDS RECEIVED

- 2 Commit awards at Jifflenow in the year 2018 and 2019 for my contributions towards the new features and deliveries
- Syncron Spot Award 2020, for contributions towards the team's release
- 1st & 2nd position in Syncron photography competition for different categories

ANIRUDH UK

SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER

PERSONAL PROFILE

Overall 6.5 years of experience in front-end development and web technologies. Experience in setting up multiple projects from scratch, contribution towards POCs of the organization, and key decision making. Everlasting hunger to learn and grow.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Syncron Software India Private Limited | Senior Software Engineer | UI Developer

Oct 2019 - present

- Lead multiple products from scratch within the organization, like Analytics tool, Admin Dashboard, Machine learning configurator UI, and Price optimization tool
- Responsible for planning and setting up the groundwork for the project, including a few key decisions like folder structure, tools, and packages to be used, lazy loading, initial setup, route planning, and generic error handling mechanisms.
- Reduce tech debts involving refactoring tasks across all the products, like cleanup of unused packages, unnecessary API calls, reusable components, etc.
- Initiated and owned the decision to move and deliver the product features from NGX-charts(which existed for around 2years in the product) to Highcharts.
- Worked on Nx-workspaces(mono-repo), Storybook configurations, angular to graphql workspace setup, and jest configurations for projects from scratch.
- Worked on multiple POCs on AG-grids, AWS-Amplify, Highcharts, React-hooks, Packaging tools, Rxjs etc.
- Responsibilities also included communicating Api schemas and appropriate designs for handling usecases.
 Communication with products team ad UX teams for feasibility checks, prioritizations etc.
- Taken up responsibility for constantly upgrading the applications from angular 7 to 8 to current 12.x version



HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Passionate Trekker and Traveler

Writing small blogs

Wildlife photography

Bird watching and its behavioral study

Conducting workshops for awareness sessions on wildlife and environment

Working with local NGOs for social cause and also wildlife conservation

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth: 21st Feb 1993

Languages spoken: English, Kannada, Hindi, Tulu and Telugu

Marital status: Single

ANIRUDH UK

SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER

WORK EXPERIENCE

JiffleNow | Software Engineer | Senior Software engineer | UI Developer

June 2017 - Oct 2019

- Our team was responsible for integrating our product with external CRM tools and coming up with generic UI to configure respective parameters.
- Also worked on Salesforce integration and providing similar features as of webApp on salesforce App.
- Worked with the core UI team of the company, responsible for migrating features from old tech-stack to React.
- Owned multiple products and their entire functionality till delivery and was also responsible for any further enhancements and fixes around the feature.
- Worked on React, Ag-grid, and Redux
- Since many functionalities were on the old tech stack, there were a lot of technical debt and had owned up and delivered them for better experience.

Oracle | Associate Software Engineer

Oct 2015 – June 2017

- Started off with my first project as UI Developer, using Jquery, knockoutJS, requireJs and Oracle internal tool
- Collaborated with other designers
- Translated requirements into polished, high-level designs

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

PESIT – South campus (VTU) | 74.72% (VTU)

Bachelor's in Computer Science Engineering | Sept 2011 - July 2015

Sri Chaitanya (Andhra Pradesh board) | 88%

12th Grade | April 2009 - April 2011

Kendriya Vidyalaya (CBSE) | 81.5%

10th Grade | April 2009